Inventory of the Johanna Gostas POW/MIA papers, 1963-1974
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Johanna Gostas POW/MIA papers
1963-1974
Gostas, Johanna.
05497
3.42 cubic feet (10 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
This collection contans materials related to Mrs. Gostas' work in POW/MIA issues.
Biography of Johanna Gostas
Johanna Gostas, of Sheridan, Wyoming, was the Wyoming coordinator for the National League of Families of American Prisoners and Missing in Southeast Asia. Her husband, U.S. Army Major Theodore W. Gostas, was taken prisoner by the North Vietnamese during the Tet Offensive in February, 1968, and was released in March, 1973, following the signing of the Paris peace agreement in January, 1973. Johanna Gostas worked with national and state POW/MIA groups from 1968 to 1973, and was a National League of Families representative to a 1971 conference on prisoner of war treatment held in Geneva, Switzerland.
Scope and Content
Collection contains correspondence, news releases, pamphlets, bumper stickers, newspaper clippings, and printed materials from various state and national groups related to Gostas' work on POW/MIA issues; correspondence from other POW wives and families; posters depicting Wyoming POWs; materials related to the Geneva conference; notes and drafts; and miscellaneous memorabilia.
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
There are no known other archival collections created by Johanna Gostas at the date of processing.
Finding aid available in repository.
Mrs. Johanna Gostas in 1974.
Access Terms
Gostas, Theodore William.; National League of Families of American Prisoners and Missing in Southeast Asia.; Wyoming Cares POW-MIA.; Conference of Government Experts on the Reaffirmation and Development of International Humanitarian Law Applicable in Armed Conflicts.; Prisoners of war -- United States.; Prisoners of war -- Vietnam.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Prisoners and prisons, North Vietnamese.; Prisoners of war -- Family relationships.; Prisoners of war -- Wyoming.; Political activists -- Wyoming.; Wyoming -- History -- 1946-; Sheridan (Wyo.) -- History.;; Political activists.
Wyoming; Politics, Government, and Law; Military; Civic Activism
- American Legion, undated (Box 1)
- “American Prisoners of War in Southeast Asia, 1971: Hearings Before the Subcommittee on National Security Policy and Scientific Developments”, April 1971 (Box 7)
- Cares for POW/MIA (other states), 1970-1972; undated (Box 1)
- Cares for POW/MIA (Wyoming), 1970-1972; undated (Box 1)
- “Communist Treatment of Prisoners of War: A Historical Survey” Booklet, 1972 (Box 7)
- Concerns for Prisoners of War, Inc., 1971; undated (Box 1)
- Congressional Material, 1969-1971 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1969-1972 (Box 4)
- Disabled American Veterans, 1970; undated (Box 1)
- “Don’t Let Them Be Forgotten- POW’s-MIAs” by Wyoming Cares Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 8)
- “Don’t Let Them Be Forgotten- POW’s-MIAs” Mini Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 8)
- “Don’t Let Them Be Forgotten- POW’s-MIAs” by Wyoming Cares Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 8)
- "Don't You Let 1600 American Prisoners of War & Missing In Action Be Forgotten" Address Stickers, undated (Box 8)
- “Do You Remember Them? American Prisoners & Missing in S.E.A.” flyer, undated (Box 8)
- "Federal Benefits…for Veterans and Dependents" booklet, March 1971 (Box 7)
- Forgotten Americans Committee, 1971-1972; undated (Box 1)
- Form Letters, undated (Box 1)
- "Hearing on Problems of Prisoners of War and their Families" booklet, 1970 (Box 7)
- "Have A Hear Hanoi" Stickers, undated (Box 8)
- Have you Forgotten Them? How Can You Help?" Poster, undated (Box 10)
- "Help 1700 Men POW's-MIA's" Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 8)
- International Red Cross, 1963-1972 (Box 2)
- Mail Campaign Addresses, undated (Box 8)
- Mail Campaign Instruction Sheet, undated (Box 8)
- Mailing Lists, undated (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Mail Campaign Items, undated (Box 8)
- Miscellaneous Stickers, undated (Box 8)
- "Mother and Father and a Empty Mailbox" Postcard, undated (Box 8)
- National Committee for Responsible Patriotism, undated (Box 2)
- National League of Families of American Prisoners & Missing in Southeast Asia, 1970-1973 (Box 5-6)
- Newspapers, 1970-1972; undated (Box 8-10)
- “Our Prisoners Need Your Help! Free Them From Red Barbarism” pamphlets, undated (Box 8)
- Petitions, 1970-1971; undated (Box 2)
- POW-MIA Campaign Buttons, undated (Box 8)
- POW/MIA International, 1971-1973; undated (Box 3)
- POW/MIA Material on Major T. Gostas, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
- POW/MIA Schloarship Material, 1971-1972; undated (Box 3)
- “POW * MIA You Are Not Forgotten” Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 8)
- "POWs Never Have A Nice Day" Bumper Stickers, undated (Box 8)
- "Pray fpr Our P.O.W.'s" Forgotten Americans Committee Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 8)
- Returned POW/MIA Material, 1973-1974; undated (Box 3)
- Rescue Line, undated (Box 3)
- United We Stand, undated (Box 3)
- Voices in Vital America, 1971-1973 (Box 3)
- Veterans of Foreign Wars, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
- "Welcome Home POWs" Viva-Voices in Vital America Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 8)
- Wyoming Cares POW-MIA Pamphlet, undated (Box 8)
- "Wyoming's 9 POWs/MIAs- Don't Leave Us!" Pamphlet, undated (Box 8)
- "Wyoming's 10 POWs/MIAs- Don't Leave Us" Posters, undated (Box 10)
- “You Can Help 1500 American POW’s- MIA’s- Write Your Personal Concern for them to-“ Address Stickers, undated (Box 8)